Guide to the Dorothy Hayden Cudahy Papers AIA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. Photographs, 1918-2009; 4 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 3 flat boxes, and 2 manuscript boxes
  - United Irish Counties Association of New York, 1964, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - United Irish Counties Association--Events, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Unspecified Events, 1980s-2000s (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Unspecified Event with Ed Koch, 1980s (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Events and People, Undated (Box 49, Folder 7, Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Weddings, circa 1930s-1940s, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 69th Regiment New York National Guard Football Team G.A.A., 1935-09-29 (Box 45, Folder 3)
- Series IV. Ephemera, 1937-2006; 7 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 4 manuscript boxes, 4 flat file folders, 2 custom boxes, 4 flat boxes, and 1 packing box
  This series consists of greeting cards, newspapers, material objects, and ephemera collected by Dorothy Hayden Cudahy and John J. Cudahy. Material in this series dates from 1937 to 2006 and includes sashes worn by Dorothy at various St. Patrick's Day Parades, plaques commemorating work and achievements of Dorothy and John, and the football from the 1947 Cavan-Kerry All-Ireland Senior Football Championship held at the Polo Grounds in New York City.
  - American-Irish Legislators Society, 1989 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians St. Patrick's Day Parade and Celebration Committee, 1989-10-21 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Assemblyman Frederick D. Schmidt, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn Catholic Charities, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Cavan-Kerry football: All-Ireland Finals, Polo Grounds, New York, Sep 14, 1947; Football is located in plexi-glass box in stacks. (Box 40)
  - Cavan-Kerry football: Newspaper clippings about, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann-Martin Mulvihill Branch, 1991 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - County Clare's P. B. & S. Association, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Events, 1979-2006 (Box 49, Folder 18-21)
  - Grand Marshall Photo Album--photographs and photocopy of album, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 1-4)
  - Greeting Cards I, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Greeting Cards II, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Greeting Cards III, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Greeting Cards IV, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Greeting Cards V, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Greeting Cards VI, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Greeting Cards VII, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - The Irish World, Aug 1943 (Box 41, Folder 2-3)
  - Irish Echo, Jun 1945 - Aug 1945 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Irish Advocate, Feb 1945 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Irish American Defense Fund, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Ladies Ancient Order of Hibernians, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Mid Hudson St. Patrick's Day Parade, 1988 (Box 55, Folder 3, Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings: various, 1937, 1953-1997, undated; 1953-1997 (Box 5, Folder 27, Box 45, Folder 6)
  - New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade--Grand Marshall, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 7-11)
  - New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade--Legislative Resolutions, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade--Grand Marshall Outfit, 1989 (Box 56, Box 53)
    The outfit Dorothy Hayden Cudahy wore as Grand Marshall of the New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade consists of a green dress with matching green boots and a cream knit coat with matching pillbox hat. Photographs of Cudahy wearing this outfit can be found in the file titled "New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade--Grand Marshall" in Series III.
  - New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade--Programs, 1977-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - N. Y. Knock Shrine Committee, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Photo Collages, c. 2010 (Flat-file-folder 1, Flat-file-folder 2, Flat-file-folder 3, Flat-file-folder 4)
  - Plaques, undated; cuid34407
  - Shamrock Decoration from Danny Devlin's Tuxedo Ballroom, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - St. Patrick's Day Parade Grand Marshall Sashes, 1989 (Box 38)
  - Tickets, Badges, 1968-1980 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Traditional Irish Musicians Association, Inc., 1972 (Box 50, Folder 5)
- Series V. Commercial Recordings, 1957-1989, undated; 28.5 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 19 packing boxes
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. The recordings are arranged by format, with the bulk being 33 rpm grooved recordings and the remaining items 78 rpm and 45 rpm grooved recordings. Within these boxes there is some arrangement by artist name, but this is not consistent across the boxes. There are inventories for the 33s and 78s, and the 33s inventory contains location information. Both inventories contain title, artist, publisher, and date information, as well as record company catalog numbers.
  This series consists of over a thousand audio recordings collected by Dorothy Hayden Cudahy and John J. Cudahy for the Irish Memories radio program. The recordings date from 1957 to 1989 and were acquired by the Cudahys directly from the artists or purchased during trips to Ireland. A wide variety of Irish music is featured, including both domestic and international artists, and ranging from sean-nós singing, ceili bands, show bands, and popular songs. Musical groups represented in the collection include The McNulty Family, the Gallowglass Ceili Band, the Tulla Ceili Band, the Clancy Brothers, the Boys of the Lough, the Bothy Band, Clannad, the Chieftains, and the Wolfe Tones. Individual artists include John McCormack, Michael Coleman, Willie Brady, Delia Murphy, Anne Greehy, Michael O'Duffy, Birdie Gallagher, Carmel Quinn, Teres Duffy, Ruby Murray, Frank Patterson, Connie Foley, Mary McGonigle, Dermot O'Brien, Jackie Roche, and Paddy Noonan. Of particular interest are a collection of Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann tours of the United States and Canada, circa 1972 to 1989; two tribute albums to President John F. Kennedy and his address to Dail Eireann; and the albums of various New York Emerald Society Pipe bands.
  - 33 rpm Recordings, 1957-1989; 18.3 Linear Feet in 19 packing boxes and 1 manuscript box
    - Inventory, 1957-1989; 19 Linear Feet (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Recordings, 1957-1989; 19 Linear Feet 19 boxes of 33 rpm records collected by Dorothy Hayden Cudahy and John Cudahy for the Irish Memories Radio Show. (Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59, Box 60, Box 61, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66, Box 67, Box 68, Box 69, Box 70)
  - 78 rpm Recordings, undated; 7 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons and 1 manuscript box
    - Inventory, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Recordings, undated; 6 Linear Feet 6 boxes of 78 rpm records collected by Dorothy Hayden Cudahy and John Cudahy for the Irish Memories Radio Show. (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 71, Box 72, Box 73, Box 74, Box 75, Box 76, Box 88)
    - Dorothy Hayden Show, Irish Program Theme, "Kilkenny for Me", undated (Box 31)
  - 45 rpm Recordings, undated; 3.7 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons and 1 manuscript box (Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79, Box 80, Box 81, Box 82, Box 83, Box 84, Box 85)
- Series VI. Irish Memories Radio Program Recordings, 1944-1997; 1.75 Linear Feet; 4.1 Linear Feet in 4 media boxes, 1 record carton, and 1 flat box
  This series consists of audio recordings of the Irish Memories radio program. The recordings date from 1944 to 1997 and consist of musical selections, news, advertisements, interviews, and other segments.
  - Fidelipac Recordings, undated
    - Cartridge 170: Budweiser 1/13: 60, undated (Box 37, Item 170, Box 44)
    - Cartridge 171: Budweiser 1/13: 60, undated (Box 37, Item 171, Box 44)
    - Cartridge 172: Bud #3, undated (Box 37, Item 172, Box 44)
    - Cartridge 173: Dorothy Hayden's "Irish Memories" Theme 1'35", undated (Box 37, Item 173, Box 44)
    - Cartridge 174: D. Hayden Woodside Steakhouse: 60, undated (Box 37, Item 174, Box 44)
    - Cartridge 175: Mary Kate, undated (Box 37, Item 175, Box 44)
  - Cassette Tapes, 1944-1997
    - Cassette 106: Aer Lingus:60 50th Anniversary, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 106)
    - Cassette 107: Irish Tourist Board "$399 Fare", undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 107)
    - Cassette 108: Allied Bank (2X): 70, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 108)
    - Cassette 109: Morbert 6-6, Hennessy, Kevin O'Connor, Mar 1982 (Box 86, Cassette 109)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      This cassette is blank.
    - Cassette 110: Morbert, Kevin O'Connor, Elmer Ford, 1982-1983 (Box 86, Cassette 110, Box 42)
    - Cassette 111: "Guy LeBow at Large", re: Grand Marshall, 10 Feb 1989 (Box 86, Cassette 111, Box 42)
    - Cassette 125: Kevin O'Connor, 1983 (Box 86, Cassette 125, Box 43)
    - Cassette 130: Irish Forum with John Dearks, undated (Box 86, Cassette 130, Box 43)
    - Cassette 132: Teddy Gleason, undated (Box 42, Box 86, Cassette 132)
    - Cassette 134: Aer Lingus Inflight Program - Irish Festival (from Milwaukee), Mar 1997 (Box 42, Box 86, Cassette 134)
    - Cassette 138: David Andrews, undated (Box 42, Box 86, Cassette 138)
    - Cassette 141: Untitled, undated (Box 42, Box 86, Cassette 141)
    - Cassette 143: Kevin O'Connor, Mar 1983 (Box 86, Cassette 143, Box 42)
    - Cassette 148: Jack Irwin, Dec 1989 (Box 86, Cassette 148, Box 42)
    - Cassette 150: Bernadette Devlin, McAleskey, Kevin O'Connor, Dec 1981 (Box 86, Cassette 150, Box 42)
    - Cassette 152: Kevin O'Connor, Father Francis MacNamara, 1981 (Box 86, Cassette 152, Box 42)
    - Cassette 164: Monica Burke, LAOH President, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 164)
    - Cassette 165: Timmy O'Sullivan, Kevin O'Connor, 1983 (Box 86, Cassette 165, Box 43)
    - Cassette 166: O'Dwyer, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 166)
    - Cassette 167: Kevin O'Connor, Dorothy Interviews Rockaway Festival, 1982 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 167)
    - Cassette 168: Allied Irish Bank, New Years '44, Falker Slattery, 1944 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 168)
    - Cassette 169: Sean O'Sheicain, Con Murphy - Paddy Grimes, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 169)
    - Cassette 213: Mike Mugehy / Norbert Hennessy, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 213)
    - Cassette 214: Dorothy Hayden's "Irish Memories" - Sheila DeValera, Apr 28, 1989 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 214)
    - Cassette 215: Kevin O'Connor / Minester Peter Barry, 1983 (Box 86, Cassette 215, Box 43)
    - Cassette 216: Meeting Press, Mar 15, 1983 (Box 86, Cassette 216, Box 43)
    - Cassette 217: Broadcast of Jan 2, 1992 (Joan Hamburg Around NY) (Box 86, Cassette 217, Box 43)
    - Cassette 218: Sean MacBride / W. O'Donnel, Jan 2, 1983 (Box 86, Cassette 218, Box 43)
    - Cassette 219: Broadcast of Jan 2, 1992 (Box 86, Item 219, Box 43)
    - Cassette 220: "Her Excellency Mary Robinson, President of Ireland, Addresses the Columbia University Irish Studies Seminar; Introduction by Thomas F. Heffernan, May 19, 1993 (Box 86, Cassette 220, Box 43)
    - Cassette 221: Pat Finucane, May 1984 (Box 86, Cassette 221, Box 43)
    - Cassette 222: "A Personal Serenade to Grand Marshall Dorothy Hayden Cudahy by Phyllis Tarter, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 222)
    - Cassette 223: Dorothy Hayden's "Irish Memories" - Guest Mayor Ed Koch, Mar 10, 1989 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 223)
    - Cassette 224: Radio Free Eireann - "The Great Hunger", Oct 16, 1996 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 224)
    - Cassette 225: "Irish Memories" Guest Peter King, Nov 18, 1988 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 225)
    - Cassette 226: Dorothy Hayden Show - T. Gleason, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 226)
    - Cassette 227: William D. Griffin interviewed on WNYC's "New York Beat" re: The Book of Irish Americans, circa 1991 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 227)
    - Cassette 228: John Cudahy, Gerry Adams, undated (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 228)
    - Cassette 229: Dorothy Hayden Show - H. Goldin, Jan 20, 1989 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 229)
    - Cassette 230: Rev. Jerry Connoly, Tom Dayle, Dec 2, 1984 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 230)
    - Cassette 231: Con Howard, Jul 1, 1982 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 231)
    - Cassette 232: Kevin O'Connor, 1982-1985 (Box 43, Box 86, Cassette 232)
  - Compact Discs, undated
    - Audio Disc 1001, Tracks 1-4, undated (Box 54, Cd 1001)
    - Audio Disc 1002, Tracks 1-6/6, undated (Box 54, Cd 1002)
    - Audio Disc 1003, Tracks 1-8/8, undated (Box 54, Cd 1003)
    - Audio Disc 1004, Tracks 1/1, undated (Box 54, Cd 1004)
    - Audio Disc 1005, Tracks 1-7/7, undated (Box 54, Cd 1005)
    - Audio Disc 1007, Tracks 1-5/5, undated (Box 54, Cd 1007)
    - Audio Disc 1009, Tracks 1-9/9, undated (Box 54, Cd 1009)
    - Audio Disc 1011, Tracks 1-2/2, undated (Box 54, Cd 1011)
    - Audio Disc 1013, Tracks 1/1, undated (Box 54, Cd 1013)
    - Audio Disc 1015, Tracks 1-8, undated (Box 54, Cd 1015)
    - Audio Disc 1018, Tracks 1-5/5, undated (Box 54, Cd 1018)
    - Audio Disc 1020, Tracks 1-5, undated (Box 54, Cd 1020)
    - Audio Disc 1021, Tracks 1-7/7, undated (Box 54, Cd 1021)
    - Audio Disc 1022, Tracks 1-12/12, undated (Box 54, Cd 1022)
    - Audio Disc 1023, Tracks 1-13, undated (Box 54, Cd 1023)
    - Audio Disc 1024, Tracks 1-7/7, undated (Box 54, Cd 1024)
    - Audio Disc 1025, Tracks 1-8/8, undated (Box 54, Cd 1025)
    - Audio Disc 1026, Tracks 1-8/8, undated (Box 54, Cd 1026)
    - Audio Disc 1027, Tracks 1-15/15, undated (Box 54, Cd 1027)
    - Audio Disc 1028, Tracks 1-5/5, undated (Box 54, Cd 1028)
    - Audio Disc 1029, undated (Box 54, Cd 1029)
    - Audio Disc 1030, undated (Box 54, Cd 1030)
    - Data Disc 1031, undated (Box 54, Cd 1031)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1968-1989
    - Reel 101, undated (Box 36, Box 42)
    - Reel 102: Unidentified, undated (Box 36, Reel 102, Box 42)
    - Reel 103: "Phil Coultor" Spot: 60, undated (Box 36, Reel 103, Box 42)
    - Reel 104: Budweiser Beer: Tape BB 88-66 "Irish 1988 Revised", Aug 10, 1988 (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 104)
    - Reel 105: Pan Am: PN-82-110 "Experience/Open": 60 sec., 1982 (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 105)
    - Reel 112, Apr 13, 1975 (Box 42, Box 36)
    - Reel 113: "Dawn Over the Hills of Ireland" By Dep/Comm. James J. O'Brien, 1968 (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 113)
    - Reel 114: Allied Irish Bank: 3 Spots, 60 sec., undated (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 114)
    - Reel 115: Irish International Airlines, Jul 15, 1969 (Box 44, Box 87, Reel 115)
    - Reel 116: (Dig. CD 1006, Track 1), undated (Box 44, Cd 1006, Track 1, Box 36, Reel 116)
    - Reel 117, undated (Box 36, Box 42)
    - Reel 118, undated (Box 42, Box 87)
    - Reel 119, undated (Box 42, Box 36)
    - Reel 120: Allied Bank: 8 Spots, Jun 1979 (Box 36, Reel 120, Box 42)
    - Reel 121: Radio City: Frank Patterson, "Great Night for the Irish", undated (Box 36, Reel 121, Box 42)
    - Reel 122: Fort Worth 5, undated (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 122)
    - Reel 123: Hidden Agenda "War Film": 60 (Dig. CD 1008, Track 14), undated (Box 36, Reel 123, Box 44, Cd 1008, Track 14)
    - Reel 124: Allied Irish Bank-2 Track/Stereo, undated (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 124)
    - Reel 126: Extracts from new Michael Coleman Album – 12 inch L.P. 7 1/2" per sec (Dig. CD 1010, Track 1), undated (Box 44, Cd 1010, Track 1, Box 36, Reel 126)
    - Reel 127, undated (Box 87, Box 44)
    - Reel 128: New York 3/16/1975, Mar 16, 1975 (Box 36, Reel 128, Box 42)
    - Reel 129: Greetings: Treasa Dawson plus end of Will Reagan Show (Dig. CD 1010, Track 3), undated (Box 44, Cd 1010, Track 3, Box 36, Reel 129)
    - Reel 131: News Special: Ronald Reagan in Ireland (Dig. CD 1012, Track 1), 1984 (Box 44, Cd 1012, Track 1, Box 36, Reel 131)
    - Reel 133: Interview: John Dearie (copy of Tape 130; Dig CD. 1012, Track 2), 1989 (Box 44, Cd 1012, Track 2, Box 36, Reel 133)
    - Reel 135: Commercials: Allied Irish Bank (Dig. CD 1014, Tracks 1-3), undated (Box 44, Cd 1014, Track 1-3, Box 36, Reel 135)
    - Reel 136: Music: Seamus O'Doherty, Josephine Patricia Smith and Marie Maxwell (Dig. CD 1014, Track 4), undated (Box 36, Reel 136, Box 44, Cd 1014, Track 4)
    - Reel 137: Easter 1916 Rising (Dig. CD 1014, Track 5), undated (Box 36, Reel 137, Box 44, Cd 1014, Track 5)
    - Reel 139: Greetings: Treasa Dawson (Dig. CD 1016, Track 1), undated (Box 36, Reel 139, Box 44, Cd 1016, Track 1)
    - Reel 140: Greetings: Treasa Dawson (Dig. CD 1016, Track 2), undated (Box 36, Reel 140, Box 44, Cd 1016, Track 2)
    - Reel 142: News: Eyewitness accounts from Northern Ireland (Dig. CD 1016, Track 3), undated (Box 36, Reel 142, Box 44, Cd 1016, Track 3)
    - Reel 144: Music, undated (Box 36, Reel 144, Box 42)
    - Reel 145: Unidentified, undated (Box 36, Reel 145, Box 42)
    - Reel 146: Music (Dig. CD 1017, Track 1), undated (Box 87, Reel 146, Box 44, Cd 1017, Track 1)
    - Reel 147: Music (Dig. CD 1017, Track 4), undated (Box 87, Reel 147, Box 44, Cd 1017, Track 4)
    - Reel 149: Flag of Sien Fean, Don't Mind If I Do, Men of 20 Say Goodbye, Rattling Bog, undated (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 149)
    - Reel 151: Music (Dig. CD 1019, Tracks 2-11), undated (Box 44, Cd 1019, Track 2-11, Box 87, Reel 151)
    - Reel 153: Chieftains, "Bonapart's Retreat", undated (Box 36, Reel 153, Box 42)
    - Reel 154: "Kilkenny": Theme for Dorothy Hayden Irish Program, undated (Box 44, Box 36, Reel 154)
    - Reel 155: Johnny McEvoy Sends Greetings To Listeners In USA, undated (Box 44, Box 87, Reel 155)
    - Reel 156: Allied Irish Banks Commercials, Mar 1979 (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 156)
    - Reel 157: Irish Tourist Board Commercials, 5 Mar 1976 (Box 87, Reel 157, Box 44)
    - Reel 158: Irish Tourist Board Commercials, Mar 12, 1975 (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 158)
    - Reel 159: Unidentified, Apr 9, 1982 (Box 36, Reel 159, Box 42)
    - Reel 160, undated (Box 42, Box 36)
    - Reel 161: Lord Mayor, Desmond Jennings, undated (Box 36, Reel 161, Box 42)
    - Reel 162: Sean McCarthy, Na Sultoiri, undated (Box 42, Box 87, Reel 162)
    - Reel 163: Unidentified, undated (Box 42, Box 36, Reel 163)